<file xmlns:its="http://www.w3.org/2005/11/its" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsqti_v2p2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:qh5="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsqtiv2p2_html5_v1p0">
    <sharedstimuli>
        <sharedstimulus id="assets/d67a0fbc639ff3b315373/passage NEW.xml">
            <label key="564aa0d043747cf04bd1089ae17f60f0">
                <text>Microplastics and Marine Organisms</text>
            </label>
            <label key="aac23c2a765a682d20f8a162c8ebc9c5">
                <text>Plastic particles that are smaller than 5 millimetres in diameter are classified as microplastics.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="fd4f37892536e183816871a6fa92175b">
                <text>Most microplastics come from larger pieces of plastic that age and break into smaller fragments.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="c876d5417e7dccf38e30f3af0e66a9cb">
                <text>The use of plastics in bottles, packaging and bags has led to the accumulation (build-up) of large amounts of microplastics in the environment. This is a problem because microplastics do not easily decompose.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="c5f2b2d26a021824551aeeb99e85b432">
                <text>Microplastics do not dissolve in water and are less dense than water.</text>
            </label>
        </sharedstimulus>
    </sharedstimuli>
    <items>
        <item id="i639ff3e32d48617130656a5b94d5f41464">
            <label key="d53d4ce6210996871f0d59d9a8be2a3b">
                <text>Microplastics can accumulate (buildup) in the cells and tissues of marine organisms.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="cf7cfd9ac0991b8d02a608f0f60ac7ff">
                <text>The major source of the microplastics that accumulate in these organisms is the food they eat.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="19aff49088d97f23e2a9d3e5157de04e">
                <text>Which one of the following statements must be true for microplastics to accumulate in a marine organism?</text>
            </label>
            <label key="090b1809129081d265dd9ef847355e85">
                <text>The microplastics must resemble the organism’s natural food.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="646e6fe01c1d421ecf252ebda81e6c82">
                <text>The microplastics must be present in every item of food eaten by the organism.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="1303d728fd0dab09ebb723685db74af1">
                <text>The microplastics must be removed from the organism’s body more slowly than they are ingested.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="67cb14e3ca208390a151a1df4f7e76ef">
                <text>The microplastics must have originated from discarded single-use plastics, such as plastic drinking straws.</text>
            </label>
        </item>
        <item id="i639ff46727c8a27961e433624fa788263">
            <label key="ec21478ed5921c7a8c50624841a20311">
                <text>Amara is concerned about the amount of microplastics in the environment. As a result of her concern, she has decided to stop buying food wrapped in plastic.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="869da7eed98f3ca954f1c8b3ad878e07">
                <text>Her friend thinks that this will make no difference to the problem because the food has already been packaged and the plastic will end up in the environment anyway.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="24110dff9092d13f4aadbcd39e2fd840">
                <text>How could Amara’s action help lead to a reduction in the amount of microplastics in the environment?</text>
            </label>
        </item>
        <item id="i642245a291d44407402aea37f028fff97a">
            <label key="8ca4b6c6459a280843334288396e81bd">
                <text>Microplastics are a serious threat to marine organisms.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="88470a7252acd787e839a6878af1f20a">
                <text>This problem needs a solution so that marine organisms are not further threatened.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="67ae55e02af0294597ccbf38c22a7b25">
                <text>Are the following strategies possible ways to reduce the amount of microplastics in marine environments?</text>
            </label>
            <label key="a8c38cd5723dd799a00d4ac84d71561e">
                <text>Select ‘Yes’ or ‘No’ for each statement.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="fdc1563a8afc5411a7aba3beeb918bd4">
                <text>
                    <strong>Yes</strong>
                </text>
            </label>
            <label key="758eaa648d8250f58a4ec4251f2ea215">
                <text>
                    <strong>No</strong>
                </text>
            </label>
            <label key="55a347bf277ecdca8bac8fac316a6010">
                <text>filtration of waste water before disposal</text>
            </label>
            <label key="19a3023f59c34566ae2aec47920db6b7">
                <text>direct removal of microplastics from the seabed</text>
            </label>
            <label key="6f0d96411bebc5be00a2c5cc856f61cd">
                <text>increased recycling and reuse of existing plastic materials</text>
            </label>
            <label key="478993e9a74cb22ce9d9e04158c8f653">
                <text>advertising campaigns focusing on the use of sustainable energy sources to make plastics</text>
            </label>
        </item>
    </items>
</file>