<file xmlns:its="http://www.w3.org/2005/11/its" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsqti_v2p2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <sharedstimuli>
        <sharedstimulus id="assets/d67a0fbc63a0ffc0f3b72/passage NEW.xml">
            <label key="ddbdca39dbe9b171232d67492fa9d4dc">
                <text>UV Light Damage</text>
            </label>
            <label key="76f1e1a8b85e1e517f62e19652407a3d">
                <text>Ozone (O₃) is a gas found in the atmosphere. It forms a layer in the stratosphere, which covers the entire Earth at about 10 km to 50 km above Earth’s surface.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="029f8afe32daf8cf7a21a5f0675edc7f">
                <text>In the past, the ozone layer was partially destroyed by the release of ozone-depleting gases.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="8477dfd4e46f4ed8af4712ad1ffc2e64">
                <text>The reduction of ozone in the atmosphere caused an increase in irreversible eye and skin damage.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="a681d4631171c8fc0c91a0395a6f1348">
                <text>Many countries now ban the use of ozone-depleting gases. As a result, the ozone layer is slowly recovering.</text>
            </label>
        </sharedstimulus>
    </sharedstimuli>
    <items>
        <item id="i63a100985333e59724f2769eb566627742">
            <label key="b9e15f055dd96fe1c2bef72e9d7075d1">
                <text>How does the presence of ozone in the atmosphere provide protection against irreversible eye and skin damage?</text>
            </label>
            <label key="91c94415f8ff42c1cc95ed3cbb3b97a9">
                <text>Ozone helps human skin reflect sunlight.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="9d0a98c8f02a047eaa5c7a767f3c1f35">
                <text>Ozone reflects radiation from the Sun back into space.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="d8773e0196455c859f2681735067583c">
                <text>Ozone converts damaging chemicals from the atmosphere into safe ones.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="fac3e048c02f242660d678b5ce33da09">
                <text>Ozone reduces the level of ultraviolet (UV) radiation reaching Earth’s surface.</text>
            </label>
        </item>
        <item id="i63a100ab37f8c21574a2c35b5c81d383be">
            <label key="068d64c1ff9dd2b85b839d4934ab5b89">
                <text>The eye and skin damage because of ozone depletion in two towns was compared. Both towns had the same concentration of ozone in the atmosphere.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="4ffbc6311d8593d807014afc59894b0f">
                <text>Which of the following facts about the towns could account for any variation in the results between the towns?</text>
            </label>
            <label key="89b1c1de80f35eb0f385836481797561">
                <text>Select all correct answers.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="51a113efde55653d2eb17f6be4c5f29d">
                <text>One town has greater access to healthcare.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="9eb3b126a3aeb51cacad321160ee93a4">
                <text>The population size of each town is the same.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="e59ee982af3720376bec0aa156dbdc18">
                <text>Suncare products are more expensive in one town.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="802aec440950edcac6fa0b3db8e58037">
                <text>Both towns provide education about suncare.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="c8b613cdea5867d124dc52bac2cd1858">
                <text>More outdoor work is done in one town.</text>
            </label>
        </item>
        <item id="i63a100bfdb689143005b621dd9e9ceb2b8">
            <label key="ce0f3c8526f7ab608ac60050abfd2372">
                <text>Methyl bromide is an ozone-depleting gas. In some countries, methyl bromide is used to protect imported and exported goods from insects and disease.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="1a1c045755abbc390e5a86e99851c1fc">
                <text>Which one of the following statements provides a reasonable justification for the continued use of methyl bromide?</text>
            </label>
            <label key="d85f818ad45471f0be2d41bdb304cdda">
                <text>Methyl bromide can be used until viable alternatives are developed to avoid disrupting the world economy.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="4efb3e69eb663446d5f06cef89b60c7c">
                <text>Methyl bromide can be used because finding alternatives will be too expensive and time consuming.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="ea04167f4f113d816b2f279902b2a63f">
                <text>Methyl bromide can be used because the ozone layer is recovering and therefore ozone depleting chemicals are no longer a problem.</text>
            </label>
            <label key="d2be0041339348062a8ca5bfdf87bc16">
                <text>Methyl bromide can be used because humans will eventually evolve immunity and will no longer be affected by UV radiation.</text>
            </label>
        </item>
    </items>
</file>